[panting]
There you are!
- [panting]
- Anne!
I'm so glad to see
that you're safe!
It's Challe!
He needs help, now!
Hurry, or Lafalle's
going to kill him!
Please, Lusul. Please!
[grunts]
[gasps]
♪
[groaning]
Is it painful?
That's your punishment
for insulting me
and taking the side of a human.
[scoffs]
[groaning]
This is so pitiful.
Why did I believe that we could
respect each other as kings
or that you and I
could love each other?
- [grunts]
- [LAFALLE] How did things
turn out so ugly?
- [grunts]
- [LAFALLE] Oh, I know.
Humanity is to blame
for all of it!
[groans]
[MALE FAIRY 22A]
Master Lafalle!
Hm.
We've captured
the human girl for you.
- [gasps]
- Skillfully done.
Pay attention.
I want you to see what happens
to your dear
Silver Sugar Master.
[groaning]
This human dared
to stand between us.
- Anne!
- And now she'll pay.
- Stop it!
- [gasps]
You little pest!
♪
[shattering]
Your wing! I've got it here!
- Thank you.
- How dare you! [gasps]
What are you doing?
Master Lafalle,
please let this girl go free.
I know she's a human,
but she's kind!
You would defy me for her?
- [screams]
- [swords clanking]
Anne! Get out of here, now!
All of you! Hurry!
- Take Anne with you!
- [gasps] Challe!
You've all betrayed me!
[screams]
[swords clanking]
♪
[grunting]
[chuckles]
♪
Lafalle!
[chuckles]
[grunts]
- [rumbling]
- [clattering]
[grunts]
[Lafalle laughing]
Aren't you a pathetic sight?
Now come here.
[grunts]
[gasps]
[wind whooshing]
Good.
♪
This is the end,
Challe Fen Challe!
[horse neighing]
[gasps]
[wind whooshing]
[clip-clopping]
The humans found us.
How's that possible?
I see. About time.
Huh?
[wind whooshing]
It was you then.
Of course.
♪
I'm being betrayed
by my own allies, once again.
Of all people...
it's you.
After you'd taken my wing,
you were the person
controlling me.
You're not my ally,
so this is not a betrayal.
A year ago, I met
a 15-year-old human girl
who understood the difference.
And yet you still can't.
[LAFALLE] If I had been able
to find you before you met her,
do you think you would have
turned your blade
against me the way you are now?
[CHALLE]
Probably not.
But then such is fate.
[chuckles]
I see. Fate.
It's over, Lafalle.
♪
[gasps]
[wind whooshing]
- [LUSUL] Wait, Anne!
- [all gasp]
What's the matter?
The humans!
Soldiers? But why?
[gasps]
You can't!
I know you're all strong,
but there are too many
troops coming!
- [CHALLE] Anne is right.
- [gasps]
Don't throw your lives away.
You're here!
Oh, Challe.
[sobs]
You're all right!
Challe!
[crying]
I'm glad you're safe as well.
[LUSUL]
Lafalle? What happened?
[Anne crying]
[CHALLE]
He fell from the walls.
That's awful to hear.
♪
[Lusul grunts]
I have recovered the chest
containing all of your wings.
Take them,
escape through the back gate.
[all gasp]
[indistinct chatter]
Thank you.
But now we've lost our king.
We'd be ever so grateful
if you would become
our king instead.
You don't need a king.
You are free now.
Your futures
are for each of you to decide.
♪
This is the fortress.
But Anne Halford's in there.
Milord, please be cautious.
I understand that.
Sadly, considering
all the violence
that these fairies
have committed,
we can't afford to hold back.
Hm?
[LUSUL] I had no idea
my wing was beautiful.
I only realized it
when you said it was.
It made me feel so very proud.
[grunts]
I've chosen
to journey on with him.
I would like to see
the ocean too!
Farewell, friends!
I wonder...
if she'll make it there.
Fairies born from plants
don't live for long.
Usually a year.
But then she did consume
your sugar confections.
I'm sure she'll see the ocean.
Hm?
♪
[ANNE]
I hope you're right.
[door creaks]
- [gasps] Anne!
- [gasps]
There you are!
I missed you, Mithril Lid Pod!
Anne! You're all right!
You had me so worried!
I'm sorry,
everything's fine now.
- [heavy footsteps]
- [both gasp]
[panting]
[sighs]
You two!
You sure keep us on our toes.
I'll give you that.
You're here at last!
We've really missed you,
all of you.
Oh, Orland.
I'm doing fine.
Please don't worry.
What about yourself?
I do hope you're unharmed.
Yes!
[KAT] Would you all dispense
with the dramatics?
This is silly.
I told you that she would
come back here, didn't I?
I appreciate it, Kat and Jonas.
Thank you!
Huh? Kieth?
Welcome back, Anne, Challe.
It's good to see
that you're both safe.
What are you doing here
at Paige, Kieth?
I was helping them all
with the work.
What about Mr. Radcliffe?
It's fine.
I considered
my choice carefully
Oh, Mr. Collins, the project!
How is it progressing?
It's straight back
to work, huh?
Your first thought is always
about your sugar confections.
Come, look.
[gasps]
♪
I'm speechless.
- You did so much!
- I know.
- Every piece is here.
- [chuckles]
- Just as you ordered.
- What?
But the...
The festival is ten days away.
We finished with time to spare?
Yes.
[laughs]
[NADIR] The whole time
you were gone,
the image of our amazing
Head of Artisans
wouldn't leave our minds!
[KING] We might've gotten
a little carried away.
[VALENTINE]
This is all thanks to you.
[ANNE] They did it.
They're all so wonderful!
Everything looks perfect,
and it's done early!
[gasps]
Mr. Collins,
if we still have ten days left,
perhaps there's something more
we can do.
I've been thinking
that same thing, Anne.
So, you're in charge.
Have an idea?
[VALENTINE] We'd better
stick to snowflakes.
Nothing else would match,
you know?
That's true, but just
adding more of them
seems kind of boring.
If we're going to do something,
then we might as well make it
as big and bold as possible!
I think so, too.
Let's make it count.
♪
All right! We'll make it bold!
[all cheering]
You'd like to start bringing
the pieces three days early?
If you don't mind.
We've done everything
except assemble them.
I promise, it'll be
the grandest decoration
the Holy Beginnings Festival
has ever had!
Hmm.
[BRIDGET]
What are you doing?
Miss Bridget, it's you.
I'm just looking at the moon,
nothing more.
- You might catch a cold.
- [gasps]
Is that...?
I just never got to return it.
[chuckles]
By the way,
I broke off my engagement
to Mr. Collins.
Huh?
What happened?
Like you said,
I should think about
what I can do now,
and in my current
circumstances.
I tended to Orland's injuries,
then watched over the others.
It made me realize something.
I truly love this workshop,
and I love every person
who's a part of it.
Elliott is a brilliant artisan.
So, when my father suggested
we get engaged,
I didn't object at all.
But the truth is,
I didn't do that
because I desired to.
I was just suffocating,
in a way.
I told my father
he should take Elliott in
as an adopted son and let him
take over the workshop.
That would be best for Paige.
And best for me, as well.
Oh, how did Mr. Glen respond?
He fully understood it all.
And Elliott said,
"Bridget's demands
usually cause me
a great deal
of grief and headache.
But for the first time,
I am inclined
to go along with them!"
Word for word.
Hm.
[laughs] That does sound like
something he would say!
Right?
[both laughing]
[KING] All that's left
is the Paige Workshop finale!
Hm.
[laughs]
Time to begin!
Start with the biggest!
Two of the white flakes!
♪
[snoring]
- [CHALLE] Anne.
- [gasps]
Challe.
You're awake? Why?
I don't know, I couldn't sleep.
Oh, well.
I'm confused.
Lafalle said that
he was the fairy king.
And he said
you were the fairy king too.
How is that?
Apparently,
we were both born
from stones gathered by Riselva
to produce the next fairy king.
Or at least,
that's what Lafalle thought.
If that's true, then you're...?
I don't know if it means
anything for me at all,
but either way,
becoming a king isn't easy.
Perhaps the time will come
when I'll need to take
some kind of action,
but not now.
[ANNE]
Then, what is it time for?
What are you going to do?
Keep my promise.
Stay with you.
So, you can be happy
and free to live your life
to the fullest.
I'll be at your side... forever.
Do as you please to.
Go where you wish,
find someone you love.
I'll support you, Anne.
[ANNE]
Someone... I love?
♪
[ANNE]
Thank you, Challe.
But if I ever did end up
being perfectly happy one day,
there'd be no reason left
for you to protect me.
So, Challe...
if that happens,
then it'll be your turn
to live a good life.
Do as you please to,
go where you wish,
and find someone you love,
as well.
To be honest, I wish
you could do that now, but...
I'm sorry, Challe.
I've caused a lot of trouble
for you.
Forever means?
Huh?
Well... if that's what
you truly want.
Now finish the final piece
of your work
and bring good fortune
to the whole kingdom,
just as you planned.
Right.
[ANNE]
The fairy king considered
King Cedric to be a friend,
and Cedric saw the fairy king
as a friend, just the same.
Side by side, the two rulers
searched for a path
that humans and fairies
could walk together.
Sadly, that dream
never came true.
But Cedric had crafted
sugar confections
for the late Riselva,
and those creations
gained the power
to bring good fortune.
♪
[ANNE]
I'll place it up high,
so that the prosperity
this sugar confection attracts
will reach every person
who resides in this kingdom.
Bring blessings to each human
and each fairy, as well!
[MALE PRIEST 24A]
Happy New Year to all!
May fortune smile upon you
and your loved ones.
Ha!
♪
- [Anne gasps]
- [people laughing]
- It's beautiful.
- So beautiful.
- [gasps]
- My word!
With that scale, you would
assume it was built right here!
And the arrangement
of the lighting.
It's turned the church
into a snowy landscape!
It's true.
Sugar confections
are wonderful!
Such great potential!
♪
[HUGH]
I'd call that a success.
[gasps]
Hugh.
This will be a resurgence
for the Paige Workshop.
They'll be quite busy soon.
I'm so glad!
I see. Glad.
Does this mean you're content
with just that, then?
Huh?
If you, Anne Halford,
plan to continue working
in the same capacity at Paige,
that's perfectly fine.
But what does
Silver Sugar Master
Anne Halford think about it?
[HUGH] You've yet
to accomplish a single thing
that's purely for yourself.
Pardon me, Viscount.
Are you flirting
with my Head of Artisans here?
I'd intended to,
but your prattling
would be too exhausting.
I suppose I'll be going.
[ANNE]
I hadn't thought about it.
I knew I'd stay with Paige
until the
Holy Beginnings Festival.
But now that that's over,
I'm not so sure.
What do I want
as a Silver Sugar Master?
Let me guess,
the Viscount must've put
another idea into your head.
So, what's the plan?
Uh, well, you see...
[chuckles]
Look, Anne, you've done
more for us than you can know.
Thank you for everything.
In return,
here's a bit of advice!
If you're planning
for your future,
I'd say you should build up
even more experience.
The Paige Workshop
is a small world.
If you want to become
the best artisan you can be,
there's more for you out there.
Mister Collins.
Well, formalities aside.
If you ever feel like
things just aren't working out,
we will always have
a place for you here.
I think I might leave
the Paige Workshop.
If you do, then what?
Huh?
What are you planning
to do next?
Back to selling
sugar confections
out of your wagon?
Oh! Um, well, I don't know.
Possibly?
As expected,
you started talking
without thinking
through it first.
Once a scarecrow,
always a scarecrow.
I mean, I have thought
about it a little!
[CHALLE]
Do as you wish.
Huh?
I'll follow you anywhere.
Thank you.
- And I'll be there too!
- [laughs]
You're not leaving
without the magnificence
that is Lord Mithril Lid Pod!
Great!